Guide to the American Wine Society records, 1967-2003
American Wine Society records, 1967-2003
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
American Wine Society Records, 1967-2003
RMC Staff
2 cubic feet
Correspondence, Publications, Printed material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Historical records, documents, and publications from American Wine Society from 1967 to 2003
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The American Wine Society records from 1967 to 2003 contains many documents from the Society, including its meeting records, publications, letters, documents, tax returns, and more. Some of the print are formally presented, such as the meeting records or the numerous publications by the Society. Others are very personal, such as letters between various members of the Society, many from three individuals, Margaret Jackisch and Angel Nardone, who were both executive secretaries of AWS, and A.W. Laubengayer, the first president of AWS. Minutes of the Board of Directors' meetings, Executive Advisory Board meetings and General meetings of the American Wine Society from its founding in 1967 until 1995.
SUBJECTS
Names:
American Wine Society.
Subjects:
Wine industry. United States; Viticulture. United States.; Wine and wine making. United States. Law and legislation.; Wine. Marketing.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- AWS Board of Directors Meeting Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  A.W. Laubengayer, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors Meeting Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  R.A. Dickmann, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors, Executive Board of Directors, and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  C.W. Damoth, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Jerry S. Miller, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Kathryn Froelich, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  J.P. Nardone, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  John Hasson, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Michael Farren, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Lewis H. France Jr., President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Tom Iezzi, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Al Long, President of AWS
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Presidents Stephen R. Kampers and J. Randy Hurteau
- AWS Board of Directors and Executive Committee Meeting Reports, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Presidents Alcide L. Porell, George E. Wilson, and Kenneth P. Brewer
- Various Documents, 1968-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Newspaper clippings, membership lists, conference agendas and registrant lists, letters, drafts of by-laws, conception and values of AWS, "Grapes and Wines in Eastern U.S.A."
- AWS Tax Exemption Documents and Applications, 1968-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  New Jersey, Tennessee
- AWS IRS and Tax Exemption, 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Letters, forms, notices
- AWS Historical Information, 1973-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Articles of Incorporation, letters, IRS documents
- Chapter Program Manual, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Randy Hurteau
- Manual for Chapter Chairpersons, Regionals, Vice Presidents, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Binder includes a floppy disk and a draft of the manual
- AWS Election Documents, 1984-2003 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Election procedures, voting ballots, instructions, pamphlets
- American Wine Society binder, January 1983 - November 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Copy of Board of Directors, Executive Advisory Board, and Annual Membership Meetings Minutes
- Letters from Margaret Jackisch, 1973-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Letters between Angel Nardone, between A.W. Laubengayer, AWS Vintage Chart Update 1918
- Konstantin Frank (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Letters between Laubengayer and other various correspondents, newspaper clippings
- AWS Publications (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Pamphlets, dictionaries, articles, etc. about or by AWS. Includes Dictionary of Wine Terms, Home Wine and Beer Makers Information, etc.
- "Understanding a Vintage Chart" and updates 1982-2000, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Written and updated by Richard D. Schneer
- AWS letters, certificates, photos (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Binder from Angel Nardone, Executive Secretary of AWS, part 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Order preserved the way it was in the binder
- Binder from Angel Nardone, Executive Secretary of AWS, part 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Complete file of VINTAGE, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Directory, VINTAGE volumes, Special Bulletins (1971)
- Annual Conference Documents part 1, 1973-2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  From binder, with some older documents in a separate folder in the binder
- Annual Conference Documents part 2, 1973-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Wine Competition and Judging Information, 1984-2003 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Also includes several articles and vintage chart updates
- Certificate of Copyrights, 1974-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Certificate of Copyright Registration for American Wine Society Journals